travelindex.com 2011-05-25

# Travel Index | Travel Directory | Connecting Travel People | Search results

[Home](http://www.travelindex.com/index.html) > Privacy Policy

## Travelindex Privacy Policy

The policy below is applicable to all Travelindex sites and to Travelindex.com in general.

Travelindex is committed to protecting the privacy rights of those who visit our site. We will not collect personal information about you just because you visited this site. Please read the following statement to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of Travelindex website.

Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our websites. We use aggregated (gathered up data across all user accounts) information to develop content targeted to users' interests and to better the website user experience. Travelindex is committed to your privacy and other than as provided herein or after receiving your specific consent, Travelindex will not share any personal information with any third party at any time, unless required by law.

**Privacy Policy Scope**  
This privacy policy is applicable to all Travelindex and related websites (eg. BestDestination.com) and subscriptions to newsletters on these and relates sites. Other Travelindex sites linked to from this website may have their own privacy statements which can be viewed on those sites.

Please be aware that Travelindex listed businesses, sponsors, advertisers, co-branded website or websites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you on their websites. The information practices of those parties are not covered by this privacy statement. Travelindex users should also be aware that, when you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards, that information may be collected by others and may result in unsolicited messages from others.

**Gathering of Information**

**Voluntary Submission**  
We do not collect personally identifying information about any individual website user except when knowingly provided by such individual. For example, we may ask you for information, such as your e-mail address, gender and the country of residence when you register to become a user of Travelindex.com. You may also provide information to Travelindex.com in other contexts, including, for example, in order to enter into a draw, competition, sweepstakes or promotion. You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still visit most of the Travelindex.com website, but you may be unable to access certain options and services. When you register or become a user of Travelindex or provide information in any other manner, you agree to provide only true, accurate, current and complete information.

**Cookies**  
Cookies are bits of information stored on your computer when you visit a website. Cookies can be used to store your personalized information such as username and password. At any time, you may choose to use, or not to use, this type of cookies technology to perform personalization on our site. If you choose not to, you must always manually log in to your profile each time you visit the site. Most website browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser settings to display a warning before accepting a cookie, or to refuse all cookies. However, if you choose to disable the receipt of cookies from our website, you may not be able to use certain features of the site. Visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) to learn about how to delete and control the use of cookies.

Business partners of Travelindex and vendors providing hosting and other services for Travelindex, as well as advertisers who contract directly with a third-party service to serve their advertisements on our websites may set their own unique cookies on your browser. We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they may contain.

**Browser Level Information**  
One method of collecting aggregate information about your activities online (such as the pages you access most frequently or the search terms you enter), and information volunteered by you (such as survey or registration information), is by tracking Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you surf the Web. The computers that deliver the Web pages to you automatically identify your computer by its IP address. When you request a page from one of our sites, our servers log your IP address. Travelindex sites record IP addresses for the purpose of system administration and to provide aggregate data to advertisers about the volume of use on our sites. We also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our websites. In addition, your IP address is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information.

 **Use of Information**  
Our primary goal in collecting user information is to enhance your experience on our website.

_To Target Content_  
To develop content targeted to your interests, we use aggregated user information to determine which areas of our website users prefer based upon traffic to those areas. We do not track what individual users read, but instead how well each page or content area performs overall.

_To Provide Interactive Communications_  
To enhance your experience we may provide you with interactive communications, such as electronic newsletters. Such interactive communications are provided only to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to receive them as part of their user profile.

From time to time we may provide e-mails highlighting new features, promotions or contests on the website to those users who have expressly provided us with their permission to send such communications as part of their user profile.

 _To Provide Communications From Third Parties_  
We respect the privacy of our users and shall not disclose or distribute our user list to any third party, nor shall it permit anyone else to do so. However, we do make available for rental our list of those registrants who have expressly provided us with their permission to receive third party information and offers as part of their user profile. Your personal information is never transferred or disclosed to the third party.

 **Control of Information**  
Users may change their user profile to stop receiving newsletters or marketing material from Travelindex or on behalf of external third party business partners. Users may choose to stop receiving such communications at any time by visiting the "My profile" page at [http://www.travelindex.com/myprofile](http://www.travelindex.com/community.cgi)

**Providing Services to Users and Members** We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of newsletter mailings, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. In some instances, one of these companies may collect information directly from you; in these cases, you will be notified of the involvement of the external service provider and have the option to stop the transaction or process. In all cases, these companies are subject to agreements that require them to maintain the confidentiality of your information and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

 **Sale of Business or Bankruptcy**  
The ownership of Travelindex may change at some point in the future. Should that occur, we want this site to be able to maintain a relationship with you. In the event of a sale, merger, public offering, bankruptcy or other change in control of Travelindex your information may be shared with the person or business that owns or controls our websites. Opting out of receiving information from third parties will not affect our right to transfer your information to a new owner, but your choices will continue to be respected regarding the use of your information.

 **As Required By Law**  
Travelindex may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with legal process served on Travelindex or to protect and defend the rights or property of Travelindex.

**Security**  
Your information is stored on Travelindex servers located in the United States. We use procedural and technical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy, including encryption, firewalls and Secure Socket Layers. We treat data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company.

**Privacy of Children**  
No information is permitted to be either submitted to, or posted on our sites by users under the age of 13. Travelindex relies on our users to be truthful in responding to the question of age. Travelindex will not provide any personally identifying information about users under the age of 13, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever without first requesting parental permission. In the event that we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information from our database as quickly as possible.

**Change of this Privacy Policy**  
This statement may change from time to time, so please check back periodically. If we are going to be using the information collected from users in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will send affected users written notice of the change by e-mail.

Under no circumstances, including but not limited to negligence, shall Travelindex be liable for any special, incidental or consequential damages that result from the use of the information or materials on Travelindex sites.

**USE OF THIS SITE SIGNIFIES YOUR UNDERSTANDING AND AGREEMENT TO COMPLY WITH THE ENTIRE PRIVACY STATEMENT.**

If you have any questions regarding our privacy statement, please feel free to contact us here. We read every message submitted and try to reply promptly.
